Rudyard Kipling Collection
Rudyard Kipling Collection
- Correspondence
  - Price, Mr., undated; includes typed transcription (Box 5)
  - Ramsay, Mr. [Allen], 1918 (Box 5)
  - Rawlinson, A.R., 1934-1935 (Box 5)
    See also Correspondence: Third party: Geoffrey Barkas.
  - Raymond, Ernest, 1935-1936 (Box 5)
  - Reith, Captain J.M., 1930 (Box 5)
  - Reuben Best Co., 1896 (Box 5)
  - Reynolds, L., 1924 (Box 5)
  - Ritter, Captain Morgan, 1902 (Box 5)
  - Robinson, [Harry] Perry, 1928; regarding a chapter Kipling wrote ("The Silent World") for the book War Graves of the Empire (Box 5)
  - Rochy, Jean, John, and Peter, 1929 (Box 5)
  - Rodd, Lady Lilias Georgina, 1909; 1915 (Box 5)
  - Rodd, James Rennell, 1909; 1917,; 1923-1924 (Box 5)
    See also Correspondence: Third party: Morris, Mowbray Walter.
  - Rogers, Mrs., 1930 (Box 5)
  - Rolfe, C.W.N., 1900; 1910 (Box 5)
  - Rosher, Frank, 1914 (Box 5)
  - Rubin, Mr., 1932 (Box 5)
  - Runtree, Fred, 1909 (Box 5)
  - Rutter, 1901 (Box 5)
  - Sanders, Bernard, 1934-1935 (Box 5)
  - Scott, [Frank Hall], 1894 (Box 5)
    See also Correspondence: Third party: Scott, Frank Hall.
  - Scott, Mr., undated; Kipling's note to Scott written on back of telegram from Doubleday to McClure (Box 5)
  - Scottish Provident Institute, 1909; includes typed transcription (Box 5)
  - Scribner, [Charles], 1906 (Box 5)
  - Scribner's Magazine, 1894 (Box 5)
  - Seccombe, Thomas, 1909; contains both original letter and photocopy (Box 5)
  - Sedgwick, Ellery, [1918] (Box 5)
  - Shee, Mr. (of the National Service League), 1910 (Box 5)
  - Shields, James Van Allen, 1924 (Box 5)
  - Sington, Mrs. [Louise?], 1892-1899; 1902-1903,; 1907,; 1916,; 1920-1925; 3 folders (Box 5)
  - Sitwell, Colonel, 1917 (Box 6)
  - Sladen, Douglas, 1910; 1912 (Box 6)
  - Smith, Mr., 1919 (Box 6)
  - Smith, Sir James Dunlop, 1917 (Box 6)
  - Smith, Miss M.M., 1922 (Box 6)
  - Smith, W.J., 1902-1904; mostly relating to Rottingdean, where Kipling briefly lived before Bateman's in Burwash (Box 6)
  - Smith & Winchester, 1895 (Box 6)
  - Smither, W., 1912 (Box 6)
  - Snow, [ ], 1932 (Box 6)
  - Spearing, Mr., 1898 (Box 6)
  - Spencer, Walter T., 1900; written by Kipling's secretary, Sara Anderson (Box 6)
  - Squire, [J.C.], 1927 (Box 6)
  - Stanley, Ursula [Kipling's goddaughter], 1924; 1927-1929 (Box 6)
  - Steed, [Henry] Wickham, 1935 (Box 6)
  - [Sterling, General John Barton], 1912 (Box 6)
  - Stuart, J., 1894 (Box 6)
  - Sutherland-Harris, [Col.] A. [Kipling's next door neighbour in Burwash], 1904-1908; 1911-1912,; 1916,; 1920,; 1923,; 1926,; 1929,; 1934,; undated; 3 folders (Box 6)
  - Swezey, Mr., 1927 (Box 6)
  - Swope, Herbert B., 1914 (Box 6)
  - Sydenham, Lord, 1918 (Box 6)
  - Tait, W. Cumming, 1933 (Box 6)
  - Tallents, Stephen, 1926-1930; 1935 (Box 6)
  - Thompson, Rev. G., 1916 (Box 6)
  - Tomalin, Mr., 1905 (Box 6)
  - Tregaskis, James, 1917; 1931-1932 (Box 6)
    See also Correspondence: Third party: E.V. Lucas.
  - Trevor-Battye, [ ], 1921 (Box 6)
  - Trotter, [ ], 1911; 1915-1916,; 1920 (Box 6)
  - Trotter, Mrs. A.F., 1924 (Box 6)
  - Trotter, Mrs., 1899; 1903 (Box 6)
  - Unman, J. Fisher, 1894 (Box 6)
  - Unwin, Edwin, 1917 (Box 6)
  - Vaux, C. Bowyer, 1913 (Box 6)
  - Vedrenne, Mr., 1913 (Box 6)
  - Villares, Senor, 1927 (Box 6)
  - Wakefield, Sir Charles, 1916 (Box 6)
  - Walford, M.E. [Mary Elizabeth] [Kipling's secretary], 1930-1931; 1935,; undated (Box 6)
  - Walker, Lady, 1915 (Box 6)
  - Walker, Mr., 1901 (Box 6)
  - Walker, P.M., 1926 (Box 6)
    See also Correspondence: Third party: George E. Vincent.
  - Wallis, H.M., 1932 (Box 6)
  - Warne, Browne [Alfred J.], 1904 (Box 6)
  - Watson, [J. Porter], 1900; 1907,; 1910-1911,; 1925,; 1929 (Box 6)
    It is unclear if these were all in fact sent to the same person, especially regards the 2 latter ones.
  - Watt, Mr. [A.P.], 1890 (Box 6)
    There is a good deal of Watt material distributed throughout the collection; search on his name to locate other items.
  - Wayt, A.E., 1901-1902; 1924,; undated; includes transcriptions of letters (Box 6)
    See also Correspondence: Third party: Rosenbach Co.
  - Webb, A. Patterson, 1924 (Box 6)
  - Westell, W. [William] Percival, 1911 (Box 6)
  - Wheeler, Ethel Rolt, 1910 (Box 6)
  - White, Brother [Harved E.], 1935 (Box 7)
  - White, Edward Lucas, 1893 (Box 7)
  - White, Lieutenant Commander C.E. Hughes, 1935; tipped-in letter from White and Kipling's response, in Kipling's book Sea Warfare (Box 7)
  - Whitney, Caspar, 1899 (Box 7)
  - Willard, Miss E.M., 1893 (Box 7)
  - Wilson, Alan D., 1896; 1928-1929,; 1932; includes types transcription of one letter; 2 folders (Box 7)
    See also Correspondence: Third party: Ballard, Ellis Ames, Correspondence: Third party: Martindell, E.W., and Alan D. Wilson material (below).
  - Wilson, Sir Guy Fleetwood, 1919 (Box 7)
  - Woods, W., 1898 (Box 7)
  - Wyatt, Paul, 1895 (Box 7)
  - Wynne, Mr., 1928 (Box 7)
  - Young, A.B. Filson, 1903-1904 (Box 7)
  - Young, John Carleton, 1900-1901; 1904,; 1906,; 1911; responses written by Kipling's secretaries Sara Anderson, M. Quarrier Hogg, K.E. Parker, E.R. Blaikie, and J.E. Coates; 2 folders (Box 7)
  - The Youth's Companion, 1893 (Box 7)
  - Zogbaum, Rufus Fairchild, 1896; 1899; all three items tipped in to copies of Kipling books ( Many Inventions, Barrack-Room Ballads, and Kim); 3 folders (Box 7)
  - Miscellaneous, first name only (Box 8)
  - Miscellaneous, unidentified, includes letter from Kipling to unidentified publication, with pencil and ink sketch on reverse (Box 8)
  - Family
    See also Miscellany: Letters from Kipling to his niece, nephew, and godchildren, below.
    - Bambridge, Elsie (daughter), 1956; with George P. Anderson (Box 8)
    - Bambridge, George (son-in-law), 1910; with Edward Knoblock (Box 8)
    - Kipling, Alice (mother or sister; both named Alice), 1910; with Mrs. Hales (Box 8)
    - Kipling, Caroline (wife)
      - Bensusan, [S.L.], 1936 (Box 8)
      - Black, Mrs., undated (Box 8)
      - Carnegie, Andrew, undated (Box 8)
      - Curties, Dr., 1936 (Box 8)
        See also his correspondence with Kipling, above.
      - Doubleday, Mrs. F.N., 1899; 1930,; 1936,; undated; includes one to Mr. Doubleday (Box 8)
        See also Correspondence: Third party: Ferber, Edna and Correspondence: Third party: Laffin, William M.
      - Du Chaillu, Paul, 1899 (Box 8)
      - Edwards, R.W.K., 1913 (Box 8)
      - Flynt, Henry N., 1936 (Box 8)
      - Garland, Hamlin, 1899 (Box 8)
      - Gurlitz, Augustus, 1899-1904; undated; 4 folders (Box 8)
        See also his correspondence with Kipling, above, and with John Lockwood Kipling, below.
      - Gwynne, Roland, 1935 (Box 8)
      - Macdonald, George A., 1900 (Box 8)
      - MacLaren, Ian, 1899 (Box 8)
      - McClure, H.H., 1899; 1901,; 1904,; undated; includes one addressed to Mrs. McClure (Box 8)
      - McClure, S.S., 1899 (Box 8)
      - Page, Thomas Nelson, 1899 (Box 8)
      - Penniman, Mrs. Nicholas, 1936 (Box 8)
      - Tesla, Nikola, 1899 (Box 8)
      - Trotter, Mrs., 1901 (Box 8)
      - Watson, J.P., 1900 (Box 8)
      - Watson, John, 1899 (Box 8)
      - Watt, [A.W.], 1899 (Box 8)
      - To others, by first name (Box 8)
      - Unnamed, 1895; 1899,; [1929],; undated (Box 8)
    - Kipling, John Lockwood (father)
      - Gurlitz, Augustus, 1901 (Box 8)
      - McClure, H.H., undated (Box 8)
      - Murray, Douglas, undated (Box 8)
  - Third party
    These items do not involve Kipling or any of his family. Items are arranged by name of sender.
    - Baldwin, Stanley, 1936 (Box 9)
    - Balestier, Anna S., 1899 (Box 9)
    - Ballard, Ellis Ames, 1930; 1935,; 1938 (Box 9)
    - Barkas, Geoffrey, 1934 (Box 9)
    - Barr, Robert, 1892; 1905 (Box 9)
      See also Barr's correspondence with Kipling, above.
    - Bazley, Basil M., 1955; 1961 (Box 9)
    - Birkenhead, Earl of, undated (Box 9)
    - Chandler, Lloyd H., 1936 (Box 9)
      See also his correspondence with Kipling, above; there are also numerous items in the Alan D. Wilson material, below.
    - Curtis Publishing Co., 1956 (Box 9)
    - Daily Telegraph, 1919 (Box 9)
    - Frank Nelson Doubleday, undated (Box 9)
    - Ferber, Edna, 1930 (Box 9)
    - Fuller, Henry B., undated (Box 9)
    - Gilder, R.W., 1899 (Box 9)
    - Hamilton-Russell, May L., undated (Box 9)
    - Hodder & Stoughton, 1941 (Box 9)
    - Hopkins, R. Thurston, 1915-1916 (Box 9)
    - James, Henry, 1903-1904; letters to his brother William (Box 9)
    - Kell, Copeland, 1899 (Box 9)
    - Ladies Home Journal, 1955 (Box 9)
    - Laffan, William M., 1899 (Box 9)
    - Livingston, Flora V., 1934; 1936 (Box 9)
      See also Correspondence: Livingston, Mrs. Luther S. [Flora V.] and Alan D. Wilson collection: Correspondence.
    - Lucas, E.V., 1930-1931 (Box 9)
    - Martindell, E.W. [Ernest Walter], 1928; 1951 (Box 9)
    - McClure, H.H., 1938 (Box 9)
    - Morris, Mowbray Walter, 1899 (Box 9)
    - Norton, Charles Eliot, 1895; 1899 (Box 9)
    - Pond, J.B., 1899 (Box 9)
    - Poynter, Agnes Macdonald, 1890 (Box 9)
    - Rosenbach Co., 1929 (Box 9)
    - Scott, Frank Hall, 1896 (Box 9)
    - Smuts, Jan Christiaan, 1921 (Box 9)
    - Stockton, Frank R., 1899 (Box 9)
    - Vincent, George E., 1899 (Box 9)
    - Watt, A.P., 1904 (Box 9)
    - Wilson, Alan D., 1928 (Box 9)
- Writings
  KpR numbers in this section refer to those assigned by Barbara Rosenbaum in the Index of English Literary Manuscripts (London; New York: Mansell, c1990, Vol. 4, pt. 2).
  - Prose
    - "At the End of the Passage" [KpR 1411], galley proof pages with corrections (Box 9)
    - "Below the Mill Dam" [KpR 1435], typescript manuscript (Box 9)
    - "Dis Aliter Visum" The Pioneer [KpR 1545], 4 July 1885; corrected copy of 1st publication; comments by Martindell written on inside folder flap (Oversize 1)
    - "In the Interests of the Brethren", 3 Galley proofs with corrections (Box 9)
    - "Letters to the Family", mock-up with 8 pages printed, remainder blank; printed copy with hand written notes (Toronto: Macmillan, 1910); 2 folders (Box 9)
    - Limits and Renewals, proof [A] with handwritten corrections (Box 9)
    - Limits and Renewals, proof [B] with handwritten corrections (Box 10)
    - "Naval Manoeuvres", typescript with corrections (Box 10)
    - "Plain Tales From the Hills", clippings from serialized story that appeared in The Civil and Military Gazette (British India) mounted on paper, along with a written explanation on the folder by E.W. Martindell (Box 10)
    - Preface to Andre Chevrillon's L'Angleterre et la Guerre, autographed manuscript with handwritten revisions (Box 10)
    - Puck of Pook's Hill, 1906; proof copy of first edition (London) with handwritten corrections (Box 10)
    - Soldier Tales, 13 head and tail pieces (Box 10)
    - Soldier Tales, painted illustrations (approx. 13" x 9"), matted, 10 full-size pieces (Oversize 2)
    - Soldier Tales, painted illustrations (approx. 13" x 9"), matted, 11 full-size pieces (Oversize 3)
    - "Surgical and Medical", handwritten manuscript (Box 10)
    - "The Tabu Tale", galley proof with handwritten corrections (Box 10)
    - "Thy Servant a Dog", proof (Box 10)
    - "The Visitation of the Sick", typescript with holographic corrections (Box 10)
    - "The War in the Mountains" [KpR 2219], revised typescript of first (discarded) article; 2 sets of galley proofs for the first edition, each with Kipling's corrections; 2 folders (Box 10)
    - "The Way That He Took" Parts I and II, Nov-Dec 1900; The Cosmopolitan, vol. 30, no. 1 and no. 2 (Box 10)
  - Speeches
    - Untitled, re: Thugs in India, 1 p. fragment typescript, with handwritten corrections (Box 10)
  - Verse and dramatic works
    - After O. W. the Unutterable [KpR 10], handwritten, with drawings (Box 10)
    - The Answer [KpR 29], manuscript with signature, and typescript copy (Box 10)
    - A Ballad of Bitterness [KpR 62], Dec 1883; handwritten manuscript (Box 10)
    - A Banjo Song, handwritten manuscript (Box 10)
    - The Baths of Biddlestone [KpR 92], handwritten manuscript (Box 10)
    - The Bridge-Guard in the Karroo, handwritten manuscript (Box 10)
    - The Burden of Jersualem, See Unpublished items by Rudyard Kipling.
    - A Chapter of Proverbs, See Unpublished items by Rudyard Kipling.
    - Chartres Windows [KpR 190], 1925; undated; handwritten manuscript; printed 1st edition published by Doubleday, Page, & Company, Garden City, NY (Box 10)
    - The English Way, 4 typescript pages with handwritten corrections (Box 10)
    - The Female of the Species [KpR 359], 3 typescript pages with handwritten corrections (Box 10)
    - The Five Nations, typescript (Box 11)
    - Four Feet [KpR 390], handwritten manuscript (Box 11)
    - The Gipsy Trail [KpR 418], handwritten manuscript (Box 11)
    - The Heritage [KpR 463], typescript, with autograph (Box 11)
    - The Holy War [KpR 472], typescript with handwritten corrections, signed; galley proof with handwritten corrections; 2 folders (Box 11)
    - La peinture a l'huile [KpR 584], poem handwritten and signed on photo reproduction of Kipling (Box 11)
    - The Mater [KpR 1368], photocopy of handwritten poem found in copy of Echoes (Box 11)
    - McAndrew's Hymn, in Scribner's Magazine, Dec. 1894 cover proof; original in Kipling letters, 1893 June 22 - note before KpR 691 (Box 11)
    - M.I., in Windsor Magazine [KpR 701], production material: 3 cards each approximately 14x11 in. with "M. I." verse and illustrations by L. Raven-Hill (Oversize 4)
    - Mine Sweepers [KpR 705], typescript, initialed "R.K." (Box 11)
    - Morning Song in the Jungle, photocopy (Box 11)
    - A Mother to Her Son, handwritten (Box 11)
    - Oh, Radiant Bay of Naples, handwritten manuscript in pencil in small address book; private printing (3 copies); photocopies of letters about the poem; 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Pink Dominoes [KpR 845], handwritten manuscript, initialed "R.K." (Box 11)
    - The Shepherd of Dartmoor Plain, handwritten manuscript (Box 11)
    - The Sin of Witchcraft, 7 pp. handwritten manuscript, signed (Box 11)
    - So For Some the Wet Sail [KpR 357], photocopy of handwritten poem found in copy of Actions and Reactions (Box 11)
    - Songs From Books [KpR 1111], proof sheets in slipcase (Box 11)
    - The Sons of the Widow, handwritten manuscript (Box 11)
    - South Africa [KpR 1118], typescript, signed (Box 11)
    - The Stumbling Block, handwritten manuscript (Box 11)
    - There's Never a Flood, handwritten poem, signed, with photograph of Kipling skating in Switzerland (Box 11)
    - Unpublished items by Rudyard Kipling (Box 11)
      Bound copy of "The Burden of Jerusalem" and "A Chapter of Proverbs", both signed by Sir Alfred Webb-Johnson with the inscription as "An unpublished item by Rudyard Kipling, given to me by Mrs. Kipling. Copy in the British Museum."
    - Ulster [KpR 1297], typescript (Box 11)
    - The Vampire [KpR 1306], typescript (Box 11)
    - The Years Between, 1918; 2 sets of galley proofs of 1st English edition, each with Kipling's revisions in holograph (Oversize 4)
    - Uncollected verse, typescript, possily taken from a published book; this section is titled "Some Uncollected Verse, etc." (Box 11)
  - Miscellany
    - Autographs, Kipling (Box 12)
    - Preface to unknown volume, signed by Rudyard Kipling, possibly a draft for From Sea to Sea: Letters of Travel vol. 1 (Box 12)
    - Royal Automobile Club Touring Report (Box 12)
    - Revisions of "War Graves" article, possibly the chapter Kipling wrote ("The Silent World") for the book War Graves of the Empire (Box 12)
    - Miscellaneous notes (Box 12)
- Memorabilia
  - Legal
    - Kipling's will, 25 Jan 1892 (Box 12)
    - Papers assigning Power of Attorney, 1919; relating to transfer of Cecil John Rhodes' estate in South Africa (Box 12)
  - Photographs
    - Of Kipling, 10 originals, 2 photocopies (Box 12)
    - Toomai of the Elephants, illustration, negative (Box 12)
  - Portraits and caricatures
    - Caricature of Kipling, on Royal Academy of Arts Annual Dinner seating chart, 30 Apr 1904; possibly by Sir George James Frampton; his name as well as those of others are written in pencil on the seating chart (Oversize 5)
    - Caricature of Kipling by Garretto, The Graphic, 24 Sep 1927 (Oversize 5)
    - Caricature of Kipling by Steven Spurrier, pen and ink with charcoal and white (Oversize 4)
    - Photograph of 1899 portrait painting of Kipling by Philip Burne-Jones, probably albumen; mount is signed by Kipling and inscribed with poem "The [?] Bay" 1900 (Oversize 5)
    - Portrait of Kipling by E. P. Upjohn, poster of the cover of The Metropolitan Magazine Special Autumn Number, September, with heading of "Rudyard Kipling" and "China and the Chinese War" (Oversize 5)
    - Pen and ink drawing of Rudyard Kipling by R. Mathews (Oversize 4)
    - Miscellaneous, includes several photocopies (Box 12)
- Printed material
  - Books
    - Barrack Room Ballads / Rudyard Kipling, 1926; signed R. K. to R. K.; Transferred to Rare Books for cataloging.
    - Collection de Contes et Chansons Populaires Tome XXIV Contes Birmans d'apres le Thoudamma Sari Dammazat par Louis Vossion, 1901; Transferred to Rare Books for cataloging.
    - The Heart of Japan / C. L. Brown, 1902; Transferred to Rare Books for cataloging.
    - Historical Study of the Mother Tongue / H. C. Wyld, 1906; Transferred to Rare Books for cataloging.
    - The House Building and Other Poems / Marshall Bruce Williams, 1902; Transferred to Rare Books for cataloging.
    - Kate of Kate Hall / Ellen Thorneycroft Fowler and Alfred Laurence Felkin, 1904; Transferred to Rare Books for cataloging.
    - The Loves of Miss Anne / S. R. Crockett, 1904; Transferred to Rare Books for cataloging.
    - Memoirs of a Person of Quality / Ashton Hilliers, 1907; inscribed by author to Rudyard Kipling; Transferred to Rare Books for cataloging.
    - Prophesies, Miracles, and Visions of St. Columba, 1895; title page only with inscription to Kipling (Box 12)
    - Sir Roger's Heir / F. Frankfort Moore, 1904; Transferred to Rare Books for cataloging.
  - Clippings
    - Reviews of Kipling books, 1891-1898; undated (Box 12)
    - "Seven Miscellaneous Paragraphs with Ms. notes by Author Kipling 1883-1884", collected by Martindell, with his handwritten explanation of material (Oversize 4)
    - Miscellaneous clippings, 1898-1951; undated; 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Miscellany
    - Dealer catalogues, collected by Harvey Taylor (Box 12)
    - Kipling burial service program, 23 Jan 1936 (Box 12)
    - Masonic Authors Lodge No. 3456 meeting notice, 1936; Kipling listed as an honorary member (Box 12)
    - Royal Literary Fund Anniversary Dinner, 21 May 1908 (Box 12)
  - Writings by others
    - "Cervantes, Zola, Kipling, & Co." / Brander Matthews in The Cosmopolitan, Mar 1893 (Box 12)
    - " 'Cum Laude Platypus' by John R. Ornithorhynchus" / Albert B. Fowler (Box 12)
    - Foreword to Thomas Tussser's Five Hundred Points of Good Husbandry / E.V. Lucas, 1931; reprint, typescript; notes; copies of letters to/from Lucas; scrapbook with clippings about book (Box 12)
    - "John Howell, Bookman and Collector Reveals Kipling Rarities" / Harvey Taylor (Box 13)
    - "Kipling: Laureate of the Empire" / Harvey Taylor, handwritten and typescript (Box 13)
    - "Kipling's India" / Arley Munson in The Bookman, Mar 1914 (Box 13)
    - "A late lark twitters..." / unidentified author, undated; 2 handwritten pages (Box 13)
    - "Mr. Eliot's Kipling" / Lionel Trilling in The Nation, 16 Oct 1943 (Box 13)
    - Notes of Harvey Taylor (Box 13)
    - "On Some Tales of Mr. Kipling's" / S. R. Crockett in The Bookman, Feb 1895 (Box 13)
    - "Rudyard Kipling" / William Brunton, poem (Box 13)
    - "A Series of Thirty Etchings by William Strang, Illustrating Subjects from the Writings of Rudyard Kipling" / William Strang, circa 1901; original etchings (28 of 31, wanting #10 and #28) and typescript copy of manuscript; proofs of the final states by Wm. Strang, printed and signed by Strang's son David Strang; 2 folders (Box 13)
    - "Today September the 16th 1890 I went up..." / unknown author, undated; 5 typescript pages (Box 13)
- Miscellany
  - Advertising instructions, 1906; includes handwritten note, "Typed for me by his own hand by Rudyard Kipling 23/8/06" (Box 13)
  - Bookplates (Box 13)
  - Celluloid drawing, hand painted, used in Walt Disney's animated movie The Jungle Book (Oversize 5)
  - Change purse, autographed (Box 13)
  - "Kipling Flowers", dried flowers (Box 13)
  - Letters from Kipling to his niece, nephew, and godchildren, photocopies (Box 13)
    Gift of Lisa Lewis.
  - Pipe (broken, Kipling's) [MISSING 9/10/2021]
  - Report card from Haileybury College, Mar 1874; signed by Cornell Price, later headmaster at a Kipling school (Box 13)
  - Sketches, pen and ink, by Kipling, includes photocopy of sketch from a Kipling letter (Box 13)
  - Stationery, Kipling's (Box 13)
  - Typewriter in case, Kipling's Remington Noiseless (Oversize 6)
  - Scrapbook, 1926-1936; clippings about Kipling (Box 13)
  - Scrapbooks, 1926-1936; clippings about Kipling; 3 volumes (Box 14)
  - Scrapbook, T. W. E. Moreton, includes letters from Kipling (Box 14)
  - Scrapbook, Henry H. Schlosser, relates to the printing of Ellis Ames Ballard's Catalogue Intimate and Descriptive of My Kipling Collection, privately printed in Philadelphia in 1935 (Oversize 7)
- McClure collection
  - Correspondence
    - Ballard, Ellis Ames, 1938 (Box 15)
    - Conland, Dr., 11 Jun 1899 (Box 15)
    - de Forest, L., 29 May 1899 (Box 15)
    - Watt, A.P., [1899] (Box 15)
    - Kipling family, photocopies (Box 15)
    - Miscellaneous, photocopies (Box 15)
    - Miscellaneous letters to R. Kipling via McClure, 1899 (Box 15)
  - Writings
    - "The Absent-Minded Beggar" / Rudyard Kipling, circa 1899 (Box 15)
    - "Before Kipling Becomes a Myth" / H. H. McClure, 2 Feb 1936; typescript, printed release; includes photocopy (Box 15)
    - The Courting of Dinah Shadd: A Contribution to a Bibliography of the Writings of Rudyard Kipling, 1898; private printing (photocopy) (Box 15)
    - "Do women have to be alive today.. ." / H. H. McClure, 28 Apr 1937 (Box 15)
    - "The King" / Rudyard Kipling, 1899; 1st edition American copyright (photocopy; original transferred to Rare Books for cataloging) (Box 15)
    - "Kipling's Life In America" / H. H. McClure, includes photocopy (Box 15)
    - "Mr. Kipling visited our office.. ." / H. H. McClure, 7 Mar 1899; typescript (Box 15)
    - "To the Editor, Readers' Digest" / H. H. McClure, includes photocopy (Box 15)
    - Notes on Kipling / H. H. McClure, undated (Box 15)
    - Miscellaneous, letters and statements about Kipling's suit against Putnam (Box 15)
  - Memorabilia
    - Clippings, originals; 3 folders (Box 15)
    - Clippings, photocopies; 3 folders (Box 15)
    - Photographs (Box 16)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 16)
- E. W. Martindell collection
  - Correspondence
    - Kirkman, Rev. W.A. (Box 16)
  - Writings
    - Collection of 29 uncollected Kipling verses, 1884-1906; typescript copies (Box 16)
      Contents as follows:
      "Amir Ali Locuitur," Pioneer, July 18, 1888
      "Ballad: by an Em-n-nt Lord," Civil & Military, May 8, 1886
      "The Blind Bug," National Observer, Dec. 27, 1890
      "The Bugler," The Regiment, No. 1, Oct. 25, 1902
      "The Bushman's Daughter," St. James's Gazette, Aug. 13, 1890
      "The City of Berlin," Sept. 26, 1889
      "Departmental Delirium," Pioneer, April 26, 1887
      "'An Echo from Old Calcutta'," Pioneer, March 15,1886
      "An Excellent Reason," Pioneer, May 23, 1887
      "The Half-Way House," Pioneer, Apr. 15, 1887
      "How Breitmann Became President.. .," New York World, Apr. 26, 1890
      "In Answer," Civil & Military, Oct. 14, 1887
      "The Lament of C. I. E.," Pioneer, Jan. 20, 1888
      "The Last Call," The Week's News, Mar. 31, 1888